Let's talk about the structure.
我们来看看论文结构
Do you remember grade school science fairs and learning about the scientific method?
还记得小学科学展览上学习的科学方法吗？
Well guess what, what you learned actually applies to the real world.
你猜怎么着 你所学的知识实际上能应用到实际生活中
Papers are actually structured with title, abstract,
论文的结构包括标题 摘要
methods, results, conclusions, and discussion sections.
方法 结果 结论和讨论部分
Let's start at the beginning.
我们从头开始
The very first thing that you'll read is the paper's title.
首先阅读的是论文标题
You've probably picked out the paper because the title
你之所以选择这篇论文
indicates that the topic has to do with something you care about.
就是因为标题表明论文主题与你关心的事物有关
Sometimes, it has an important keyword.
有时候 标题包含重要的关键字
The second thing that you should pay attention to is
第二个要注意的部分是
the list of authors. Why does this matter?
作者列表这个为何重要？
Well, it tells you something about the provenance of the ideas within.
作者列表可以告诉我们观点的来源
Usually, the first author is the main author,
通常 第一作者是主要作者
the person who did most of the work.
大部分工作都是第一作者的
But sometimes there are multiple main authors, indicated with asterisks.
但有时候有多个主要作者 并用星号标注
Usually, the last author is this person's adviser.
通常 最后一位作者是第一作者的指导教授
Typically, a more senior person in the field.
一般是领域内更资深的人士
The ideas in the paper maybe offshoots of this more senior person's other ideas.
论文中的观点可能是这位资深人士的其他观点的延伸
So, they may be related to this person's older papers.
所以可能与此人以前的论文有关
When there are only one or two authors,
如果只有一两位作者
it could be that this person or people are already
这些作者可能已经在此领域有所建树
established in this field and they worked on this project on their own.
他们独立完成了这个项目
Sometimes the list of authors is huge.
有时候 作者列表很长
This means that many teams of people typically in
表明有很多人合作完成了这个项目
different places around the world had to cooperate to accomplish this work.
他们通常来自世界不同地方
Okay. The third thing you'll read is the abstract.
Ok要读的第三个部分是摘要
This is a short summary of the paper.
摘要是对论文的简单总结
Sometimes this is as far as you get.
有时候 你只需读到摘要部分
The abstract should communicate basically
摘要应该会介绍
the question or problem the author tried to address,
作者尝试解决的问题
what the author did, the main important finding,
作者完成的工作 主要发现
and what they think their result means.
以及结果的含义
That is how it addresses the original question or problem.
即对原始问题的解决情况
If you read the abstract and the paper is
如果你读了摘要后发现
about something different than what you thought it was,
论文内容与你想象的不一样
or doesn't indicate that they found something meaningful,
或者并没代表有意义的发现
you can stop right there.
你就可以停止阅读了
Sometimes the abstract looks interesting,
有时候 摘要读起来很有意思
but doesn't give you enough information.
但是信息并不多
If you get past the abstract,
摘要之后
you come to the introduction.
就是引言部分
In this part, the author is supposed to give some background about the field,
在此部分 作者会介绍领域背景知识
and explain why they decided to study the topic of the paper.
解释为何对论文主题展开研究
It's supposed to help you follow the flow of ideas that led to the question,
引言可以帮助你了解引出问题的想法
which in turn led to the idea of their paper.
进而引出论文的想法
Sometimes the author does a great job at this,
有时候 作者的引言很精彩
and you can really learn something about the field in this part.
你能够在此部分学习一些领域知识
Sometimes the introduction is short and not very helpful.
有时候 引言很简短 没什么用
Often, in this section,
此部分
the paper will cite other papers that may be useful to look at to.
经常会引用其他论文 也许可以看看这些论文
The next section is usually the methods section.
下个部分通常是方法部分
Do you have to go through this line by line?
需要逐行阅读吗？
No. In fact, you can skip this entire section.
不需要 实际上可以跳过整个部分
You might skip ahead to the results and conclusions to
可以跳到结果和结论部分
know what they actually found and come back to this section later.
看看他们到底发现了什么 再回到这一部分
You might end up reading this,
如果你想知道
if you want to know that they were careful to control for some important confounding
他们如何控制某个重要的混淆变量
variable which you would care about if you were trying to decide for yourself,
而你要判断结果是否有意义的话 比较关心这个变量
if their results are meaningful.
或者如果你想重现整个或部分流程
Or you might read this, if you want to replicate what they did in whole or in part.
那么可以再读读方法部分
Next, is usually the result section.
下个部分通常是结果部分
This section should communicate the main measurements the authors made.
这个部分应该表述了作者的主要衡量结果
Ideally, everything is well labeled and clear.
理想情况下 一切都标记清晰
But sometimes it's not,
但有时候并不这样
and you have to skip back to the methods to find out what some measurement is.
你需要跳到方法部分 看看衡量值都是什么
Finally, the conclusions or discussion should communicate why the results are important,
最后是结论或讨论部分 应该表述结果为何重要
what they mean, and how they relate to the original question or problem.
有什么意义 与原来的问题有何关系